prefer uh general over life insurance
and just help us understand in a bit
more depth perhaps why uh ICICI Lombard
general and Max Financial Services are
your top picks and while we're at it how
would you characterize uh valuations
amongst uh the list of names that you
cover?
>> Yeah. Uh so uh coming on to the life
insurance and general insurance sector I
am slightly more constructive on general
insurance sector because of uh uh it has
a secular growth story uh be it from the
commercial lines of business so
engineering liability uh fire all those
lines of business I see strong growth
opportunity in that uh Swiss C also sort
of for the next five years uh the growth
projection other than the inflation
adjust ment it sees around two to 3%
higher growth for the uh PNC sector
general insurance sector. Uh so the
growth is is itself is not an issue for
uh general insurance sector but for life
insurance sector what we have seen that
the growth in the previous years was
primarily led by UNLIP uh growth uh ulip
growth and that was driven by the biant
markets. Uh but we see uh the as and
when the capital markets remain
turbulent the ulipdriven growth will be
slowing down and that is already playing
out uh and uh but that is slightly
offset by demand. the traditional
products. Coming back to uh the
companies we prefer, General Insurance,
Lombard is our preference because it is
it commands the highest market share in
the motor market. Uh it is slightly um
in terms of the valuation slightly
stretched but uh there is still a
scarcity premium because it is the only
company which is uh properly multi-line
PNC company in the Indian space. uh
estate at around so we we value it
around 5.6 time book to uh price to book
for 27 for access max life uh we we
think that it is a bit of
underappreciated story whether it
fundamentals are quite closer to HDFC
life. So if you see the the valuation
gap between HDFC life and access max
life uh there's a still pretty healthy
discount um and and the fundamentally it
is catching up. It is doing very well.
It is products very well diversified. So
it tra around 2.2 times price to
embedded value FY27. Um so we think
there's further scope for this to come
closer to HDFC life multiple. Uh and
that's the our main argument of being a
good attractive opportunity to invest
in.
>> Understood. Sat the fundamentals in
India's insurance market the prospects
are looking very strong. Swiss re I saw
a statistic here says that in the coming
five years total insurance premiums will
grow by 7.1% in real terms. That's well
above uh the global averages. Does that
sound right to you? And how much scope
for growth is there exactly? And that's
always a reflection of just how
underpenetrated or underinsured or even
uninsured households are in India.
>> Yeah. you put the right point under
insurance is a criteria that is playing
out uh but the the numbers which put out
around 8% 7 to 8% uh life insurance
slightly lower and general insurance
slightly higher uh that looks sensible
to me uh because given the u the
underpenetration in the general
insurance sector it is only 1% uh
compared to 1.9% of average
emerging market average. So I I see the
further scope for uh increasing it. Uh
also in terms of I already alluded the
point that commercial lines have a very
good strong growth scope opportunity. Uh
whether it be liability lines that has
we have only scratched the surface as
yet. Uh so fire liability lines, marine
lines, the are the lines which will see
strong and healthy growth.